A Guide to the Nan Croley Architectural Collection, 1996-2006
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Nan Croley Architectural Collection, 1996-2006
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms2006-016
1 flat box, 1 oversize folder; 0.6 cu. ft.
Nan Croley got her B.A. from Lake Erie College, and later earned her Bachelor of Architecture degree from Pratt Institute, School of Architecture in 1970. The collection consists of some biographical information and partial sets of construction drawings for three projects, several renderings and pen sketches done by the architect while employed at the firm of John Matthews Architects.
John Matthews Architects, AIA and Wendy Bertrand
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The Nan Croley Architectural Collection was donated to the International Archive of Women in Architecture at the Special Collections in 2006
Biographical Information
Nan B. Croley was born in 1939 and grew up in Cleveland, Ohio. She earned her B.A. from Lake Erie College in Painesville, Ohio, where she studied art and theater. She earned a Bachelor of Architecture degree from Pratt Institute, School of Architecture in 1970.
She worked for Finger and Moy Architects, Fisher Development, Colyer/Freeman Group and Bay Architects before starting at John Matthews Architects, a position she kept until her death. Her work included such projects as banking, retail interiors, tenant improvements, custom residences, and storefront renovations.
Croley was also active in the Organization of Women Architects and Design Professionals, a professional organization that encourages and supports women in the profession. She attended many retreats and served on the Steering Committee in 1985. She was also active in her community and supported the work of the Sierra Club.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of partial sets of construction drawings for three projects and several renderings and pen sketches by Croley drawn while employed at the firm of John Matthews Architects. Projects include a new medical building, 1996-1997, the Massolo Building storefront, 1996-1998, and a remodel and addition to Cannizzaro residence, 1997-1999. The collection also contains biographical data and office brochures about projects she worked on.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by material type. Large construction documents are stored separately in an oversized folder.
Contents List
- Biographical information, 2003-2006 (Box-folder 1:1)
- John Matthews Architects office brochure, Storefront and Commercial Design Services and Massolo building images, n.d. (Box-folder 1:2)
- Sketches for an unidentified residence, 1999 (Box-folder 1:3)
- Sketches for an unidentified residence, n.d. (Box-folder 1:4)
- Hand-drawn and colored renderings on presentation boards, n.d. (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Massolo Building storefront design
  - Straw Hat Pizza storefront design, unfinished
  - Wardrobe Cleaners storefront design, color scheme and photo on reverse
- Project construction drawings (Box-folder 1:5)
  - New Medical Office Building for Dr. Gail Tenikat and Dr. David Jacoby, San Carlos, California, 1996-1997 (5 sheets)
  - Massolo Building, Community Development Storefront Improvement Program of Millbrae, California, 1996-1998 (2 sheets)
  - Remodel and Addition for the Residence of Jim and Francis Cannizzaro, Burlingame, California, 1998-1999 (5 sheets)